Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday in question
of of question and answer where we open
up with the Ten Commandments that God
commanded the whole world to teach.
Brother James. Yes, sir.
And God spoke all these words saying, "I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above or that is in the earth beneath or
that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them
nor serve them, for I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me. And showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain, for
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Six
days shalt thou labor and do all thy
work, but the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shalt
not do any work, thou nor thy son nor
thy daughter, thy man servant nor thy
maid servant nor thy cattle nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife nor his
man servant nor his maid servant nor his
ox nor his ass nor anything that is thy
neighbor's. I read Exodus 20 verses 1
through 17. May the Lord add a blessing
to the reading of this word. In Jesus'
name we pray. Amen.
Amen.
So here on question and answer you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also
remember that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain everlasting life. We just asking
that you keep them to a two scripture
maximum per question. Let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. We got brother Jerome.
Grace and peace.
Brother Julius.
Good evening, everybody.
Brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother James. Good evening, everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
Brother Sean.
And we have the guest caller with us and
I'm brother Cornell. Sister, what is our
first question of the evening?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Victoria Smith asks, "In Numbers 13
verse 20, what does it mean when it says
first ripe grapes?"
All right, Numbers 13 and 20. Can you
shed some light, brother Dre?
Yeah, let's go to Numbers uh 13 and 20
and read that. When you get there,
brother James, would you read it,
please?
And what the land is, whether it be fat
or lean, whether there be wood therein
or not. And be ye of good courage and
bring of the fruit of the land.
Now the time was the time of the first
ripe grapes.
So the first ripe grapes, it was the
time of the first ripe grapes, and that
simply means when grapes are ripened.
And these are the first ripened grapes.
That That is what is talked about. And
what they did was they went, spied out
the land, and they brought back of the
first ripe grapes. Skip down to verse 23
and read 23 and 24.
And they came unto the brook of Eshcol
and cut down from thence a branch with
one cluster of grapes. And they bare it
between two upon a staff. And they
brought of the pomegranates and of the
figs. The place was called the brook of
Eshcol because of the cluster of grapes
which the children of Israel cut down
from thence. Yeah, the grapes were so
big that they
had to take them on a staff and bring
them back. But that's what it means, the
first ripened grapes. That's all I got.
All right.
Thank you for that, brother. Hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next one.
Next one, "I've never been married
before. When I do get married, should I
marry someone who also has never been
married
All right, let's go to Joshua 14 and 6.
And read it when you get there, brother.
Then the children of Judah came unto
Joshua in Gilgal. And Caleb, the son of
Jephunneh the Kenizzite,
said unto him, "Thou knowest the thing
that the Lord said unto Moses the man of
God concerning me and thee in
Kadesh-barnea.
All right, so we in that verse
and chapter that you gave us has nothing
to do with the word rent in there.
But assuming that you may have made a
error and what you meant was Joshua 7
and verse 6.
Joshua 7 and 6. And rent just means
merely to tear or to separate or to pull
apart. But read that Joshua 7 and 6.
And Joshua rent his clothes and fell to
the earth upon his face before the ark
of the Lord unto the eventide, he and
the elders of Israel, and put dust upon
their heads. So when it say he rent his
clothes, he just tore them or separated
them, which was a sign of humility for
Joshua before the Lord. And
that's all that I can get out of the
word rent.
And that's all I got. Anybody else want
to add to that?
All right. We're going to leave it there
and we're going to move on to our next
question.
Moving on, Zion says, "I've never been
married before. When I do get married,
should I marry someone who also has
never been married or does it not
matter?"
All right.
Never been married before, should they
marry somebody that hasn't been married
or does it not matter? Guest caller.
Can't answer that question.
That's too many uh
consequences and and uh to be taken to
get any consideration.
It's something that uh
you have to decide on your own.
Yes, sir.
Pray to the Lord.
That's it.
Pray to the Lord. All right, hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one.
Next one, Be Alert says, "The thief on
the cross, did he die for his own sins?
Some people believe you don't need to be
baptized since Jesus forgave his sins
without baptism."
Brother Julius.
It is an assumption to say that
he wasn't baptized.
And yes, let's let's go to Luke the 23rd
chapter.
And the first part of this question is
uh did he die for his own sins? Let's
see what the book say. Let's look at
let's hear it out of his own mouth.
Wages of sin is death.
Luke 23, James, we're going to pick this
up at verse 39.
Okay.
And one of the malefactors which were
hanged railed on him saying, "If thou be
Christ, save thyself and us."
But the other answered rebuked him
saying, "Dost not thou
Dost not thou fear God, seeing thou art
in the same condemnation?"
Yeah.
And we indeed justly
Read that again. And we indeed justly
Uh-huh. for we receive the due reward of
our deeds. So this guy is acknowledging
He is acknowledging
I'm I'm being tortured this way and
crucified this way for for my behavior.
Go ahead.
But this man hath done nothing amiss.
So now he
That's That's Go ahead and read it.
And he said unto Jesus, Lord, remember
me when thou comest into thy kingdom.
Uh-huh. And Jesus said unto him, verily
I say unto you, unto thee, today shalt
thou be with me in paradise. He's
telling him, I'm telling you today, when
I when my kingdom come, he said,
remember me when I come when I come into
my king when you come into your kingdom.
I'm telling you today
when I come into my kingdom, you're
going to be there. So now, the man
acknowledges transgression, but they
said that the other end of that question
says, some people believe you don't need
to be baptized since Jesus forgave his
sins without baptism.
Who says he wasn't
baptized? Let me take you to a place
here. Let's go to Matthew the third
chapter.
We don't assume at the Israel of God, we
don't assume. We read what the book say.
Matthew chapter 3. Mhm. We're going to
read verses 1 and 2 and skip. Very
important that we understand this.
Matthew 3 verse 1 and 2.
In those days came John the Baptist
preaching in the wilderness of Judea.
Uh-huh. And saying, repent ye for the
kingdom of heaven is at hand.
Skip down to verse 5 and read to 6.
Then went out of him
then went out to him Jerusalem and all
Judea Did y'all get that? Did y'all get
that? All Judea. Go ahead.
And all the region round about Jordan.
Uh-huh. And were baptized of him in
Jordan confessing their sins.
So, John baptized all the people that
was that came to him.
In Jordan and in the region. So you
can't say the thief wasn't baptized.
So now, but
the last my last place, let's go to
Matthew the 28th chapter.
It and some people say it's not
required. What did Jesus say do? Matthew
the 28th chapter. Cuz Peter told you in
Acts 2 and 38, be baptized for remission
of sins.
Matthew 28 18 to verse 20.
And Jesus came and spake unto them
saying, His disciples. Go ahead.
All power is given unto me in heaven and
in earth.
Go ye therefore and teach all nations
baptizing them in the name of the Father
and of the Son and of the Holy Ghost
teaching them to observe all things
whatsoever I have commanded you and lo,
I am with you alway even unto the end of
the world. Amen. So Peter
Peter was a man of God and he was
baptized and he understood his system,
brothers. And so all the disciples were
baptized. So therefore, Jesus said, be
baptized in the name That's what Peter
said.
Go ye and teach all nations to his
disciples.
And Peter told you in Acts 2 and 38,
repent and be baptized in the name of
Jesus for remission of sins. So it don't
matter what people say, what they think,
it only matter what the book say. Jesus
said, be baptized. I'm done with that
one.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answer their question as we move on to
our next.
Next one. Tomorrow Williams asks, in
Genesis, the Lord created the world and
man and rested on the seventh day. Did
it take the Lord
six days or 6,000 days to create the
world and mankind?
All right.
So it look like days and years are kind
of mixed up there. Brother Jerome, what
you got?
Yeah, it wasn't 6,000 days, okay?
A day to the Lord one day to the Lord is
a thousand years. So let's go read the
verse.
Uh let's go to
Second Peter
chapter 3.
And we're going to read verse 8.
But beloved, be not ignorant of this one
thing, that one day is with the Lord as
a thousand years and a thousand years as
one day.
Yeah, so
yeah, in six days he created the heavens
and the earth.
So
one day to the Lord is a thousand years,
so it took him 6,000 years.
Not six days, 6,000 years.
That's all I got.
Yep, brother Jerome, what is time when
you live forever?
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answer their question as we
move on to our next.
Our next one. Sam Burns asks, is there a
correlation between Isaiah 41 verse 15
and Psalms 148
verses 6 and 7?
All right, is there correlation between
Isaiah? Let's go to that Isaiah 41 and
15.
And when you read that
the guest caller take it from there and
then they also ask about that Psalms 148
6 and 7.
Okay. Isaiah 41 and 15 says, behold, I
will make thee a new sharp threshing
instrument having teeth.
Thou shalt thresh the mountains and beat
them small and shall make the hills as
chaff.
Guest caller.
And do you want me to read Psalm 148 6
and 7 to show the comparison? Okay.
Yeah. Psalm 1
Psalm 148 verses 6 and 7 says, he hath
also established them forever and ever.
He hath made a decree which shall not
pass.
Praise the Lord from the earth, ye
dragons and all deeps.
Mhm.
Guest caller, you with us?
All right. Um
Why don't we go and skip over that one,
sister Deborah, to the next one and
revisit that.
All right. Uh the next question is from
Cool Blue. Cool Blue asks, what does
burning sage do? I know we're not
supposed to do it,
but I tried to tell people it attracts
spirits, not repel. What does it really
do?
All right. Dre, what you say about sage,
bro?
Yeah, when you look when I looked up
sage, what it deals with is
uh
burning of a of sage is supposed to
cleanse the air of evil spirits or
negative energy.
Now, there's nothing in the scriptures
that tell us
to
burn sage. In fact, this is what Let's
go to Deuteronomy 18.
And we're going to pick it up at verse
10.
Deuteronomy 18 and verse 10.
This is what the scripture tells us.
Okay. Deuteronomy 18 and 10 says,
there shall not be found among you
anyone that maketh his son or his
daughter to pass through the fire or
that uses divination or observer of
times or an enchanter or a witch. Mhm.
Go ahead. Or a charmer or consultor with
familiar spirits or wizard or
necromancer.
There's nothing in the scripture that
tells us to burn sage. In fact, what
we're reading here says in verse 9 Read
verse 9, brother. Go ahead.
When thou art come into the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee, thou shalt
not learn to do after the abominations
of those nations. Because this is what
these nations do and the Native
Americans are known for burning sage.
Read verse 12, brother. Go ahead.
For all that do these things are an
abomination unto the Lord. And because
of these abominations, the Lord thy God
doeth drive them out from before thee.
So yeah, the Lord said in the same
chapter that he will raise up for us a
prophet and we shall hearken unto him.
And skip down and read verse 15. Go
ahead.
The Lord thy God will raise up unto thee
a prophet from the midst of thee, of thy
brethren like unto me. Unto him ye shall
hearken. That's who we should listen to.
Now, all of this sage burning
and consulting with familiar spirits and
pouring out libations calling on your
ancestors, the ancestors are sleep. You
are dealing with familiar spirits. So if
you get a return, that is from a spirit
that's not from God. I hope that helps.
Mhm.
That's right, brother Dre.
Lord said we do after them other
nations, he scattered us too, didn't he?
Yes, sir.
All right, guest caller.
Yeah, go back to the some some kind of
way I missed it.
Go back to the question.
We take it from the top, sister Deborah.
Can you repeat that question?
Yes, Sam Burns asks, is there a
correlation between Isaiah 41 verse 15
and Psalms 148 verses 6 and 7?
Answer to that is no.
Okay?
But you can read it. Isaiah 40
1 and 15.
Okay. Isaiah 41 and 15 says, "Behold, I
will make thee a new sharp threshing
instrument having teeth. Thou shalt
thresh the mountains and beat them small
and shall make the hills as chaff."
Now, this is talking about God
talking about supporting Israel
and upholding Israel even when their
enemies come before come against them.
They will make them like a threshing
tool. In other words, God says he's
going to be with Israel
and he ain't going to
uh
dispute
abandon them. That's all he's saying.
This is
saying under any all circumstances that
he was going to stand with Israel.
And Israel is going to be a weapon
be used like a weapon against his enemy.
Now, the other one
uh
6 and
7? Yes.
That says Isaiah I mean, I'm sorry.
Psalm 148 6 and 7 says "He hath also
established them forever and ever. He
hath made a decree which shall not pass.
Praise the Lord from the earth, ye
dragons and all deeps."
Now, if you went back further
it it's it's just telling you the many
things that you should praise the Lord
from. Started verse one.
Okay.
Praise ye the Lord. Praise ye the Lord
from the heavens. Praise him in the
heights.
Praise ye him, all his angels. Praise ye
him, all his host.
Praise ye him, sun and moon. Praise him,
all ye stars of light.
Praise him, ye heavens of heavens, and
ye waters that be above the heavens. Let
them praise the name of the Lord, for he
he commanded and they were created.
He No. He also No, this is
This is This is
merely telling you to praise the Lord
for all his wonderful works.
These are two different
things altogether. One saying how the
Lord going help Israel against his enemy
and here is telling the whole world and
everything to praise the Lord for all
his wonderful works that he's done.
Okay.
Yeah, that's right. Let everything that
have breath praise the Lord.
Amen.
All right. Hope that answered your
question, sister Deborah, as we move to
our next one.
Next one, Cool Blue also asks, "In
Deuteronomy 26 verse 5
the Syrian, is that Moses' father
they're talking about?"
All right, Jerome.
No, it's not Moses' father that we that
they're talking about. But let's go read
that verse. Deuteronomy 26 and 5.
Okay.
It says, "And thou shalt speak and say
before the Lord thy God, a Syrian ready
to perish was my father. And he went
down into Egypt and sojourned there with
a few and became there a nation, great,
mighty, and populous."
Okay, so now
where it says, "And thou shalt speak and
say unto the Lord thy God, a Syrian
ready to perish
was my father." That's really a allegory
that's referring to Jacob. Okay? And
Jacob is the one uh that went down
into Egypt.
Okay? And eventually
Jacob
and a whole and his whole family, the
Israelites, they went down into Egypt
and it was in Egypt that the Lord said
they he was going to make them a
a great nation. Okay? So, let's let's go
to Hosea chapter 12 and read verse 12
and then we going to go to Genesis 46
after that.
Okay.
You said Hosea chapter 12? Yeah, verse
12.
Hosea chapter 12 verse 12?
It says
"And Jacob fled into the country of
Syria and Israel served for a wife and
for a wife he he kept sheep." Yeah, so
yeah, he got his wife down there in in
Syria. Yeah. And so
then
Jacob eventually
you know he took his family, the
Israelites
to the land of Egypt. Okay? And there he
became a nation, said the Lord. So,
let's go to that Genesis 46 to see that.
Okay. Genesis. Genesis. Yeah, 46 and
read verse 1 through 3.
Okay. It says
"And Israel took his journey and with
all that he had and came to Beersheba
and offered sacrifices unto the God of
his father Isaac. Mhm. And God spake
unto Israel in the visions of the night
and said, 'Jacob, Jacob.' And he said,
'Here am I.'" Yeah, cuz Jacob's name was
changed to Israel.
Go ahead.
And he said, "I am God, the God of thy
father. Fear not to go down into Egypt,
for I will I will there make of thee a
great nation."
Yeah. Yeah, that's all I got on it.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next one.
Moving on, Brother Brett asks, "How can
I pray to God for help and ask for
things that's not repetitive?"
And Matthew 6 verse 7 is given.
How can I pray to God for help and ask
for things that's not repetitive?
Brother Julius in there Matthew 6 and 7.
James, pick it up at Matthew
6 6 and 6. Because when you pray, you
have to believe in what you're asking
for. But you also have the right
attitude. You have to exercise patience
uh
patience and you got to trust God.
Go ahead. Matthew 6 and 6.
"But thou, when thou prayest, enter into
thy closet and when thou hast shut thy
door, pray to thy father which is in
secret and thy father which seeth in
secret shall reward thee openly." So,
you have to have that kind of
attitude. You don't pray to be seen of
men. You go and because your request and
your what you're asking the Lord for is
between you and him. It's personal.
Verse 7.
"But when ye pray, use not vain
repetitions as the heathen do.
For they think that they shall be heard
for their much speaking."
So, you don't have to be repetitive
because the next verse is going to tell
you why. Go ahead.
"Be not ye therefore like unto them. For
your father knoweth what things ye have
need of before ye ask him."
Because he know what you need before you
ask. But try this right here. Verse 33
and this will be it. When you pray
go ahead.
"But seek ye first the kingdom of God
and his righteousness and all things
shall be added unto you." And all these
things, whatever you asking for, shall
be asked you. You keep his commandments.
The Lord love blessing his servants. You
keep his commandments. He told you in
St. John 14 and 14, he said, "If you ask
anything in my name, I will do it."
So, you have to have the right attitude,
understanding, and you keep the most of
all you keep the commandments and be
patient. Wait on the Lord. Don't run
before him. Wait on him. He is a problem
solver and he's a fixer. That's all I
got.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next question.
Moving on, Michelle from Louisiana says,
"Can you get Can you give me
understanding
or oracles on the difference between a
rod and a staff
in Numbers 17?"
All right. So, that question is, "Can
you give me understanding or oracles,
which are answers for our viewing
audience on the difference between a rod
and a staff?"
Well, they're very similar and and they
can be interchanged.
Sometimes it might be called a rod,
sometimes it might be called a staff,
which is also known as a a stick or pole
or rod or people even use it as a
weapon.
Um and the whole uses it as a leaning
staff.
And sometimes within that rod can
represent the power of God. But we're
not going to go all the way through
number 17. We're just going to hit a few
verses for them. There, brother James.
Go to that number 17.
And when you get there, brother, read 1
and 2. And let's see the purpose of the
Lord mentioning a rod in this chapter
and what to do with it.
Okay.
And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
"Speak unto the children of Israel, and
take of every one of them a rod
according to the house of their fathers,
of all their princes according to the
house of their fathers, 12 rods. Write
thou every man's name upon his rod." All
right. So, they had 12 rods here. And
the Lord said, "Write there upon the rod
every name." But the Lord was showing
here who it was that he wanted to
represent him. Skip down to verse 5.
Let's see what happened.
And it shall come to pass that the man's
rod whom I shall choose shall blossom.
And I will make to cease from me the
murmurings of the children of Israel
whereby they murmur against you. 7 and
8.
And Moses laid up the rods before the
Lord in the tabernacle of witness.
And it came to pass that on the morrow
Moses went into the tabernacle of
witness, and behold, the rod of Aaron
for the house of Levi was budded, and
brought forth buds, and bloom blossoms,
and yielded almonds. So, the Lord used
the rod to show that, hey, he was with
Aaron. He was going to be the
representative to cut out all that
murmuring. But let's go into um
Exodus 14. Exodus 14.
And let's see what the Lord said about
the rod here.
Exodus 14 and 14.
The Lord shall fight for you, and ye
shall hold your peace.
Mhm. And the Lord said unto Moses,
"Wherefore criest thou unto me? Speak
unto the children of Israel that they go
forward.
But lift thou up thy rod, and stretch
out thine hand over the sea, and divide
it. And the children of Israel shall go
on dry ground through the midst of the
sea."
So, the Lord told Moses lift up his rod,
stretch it over the sea, and the Lord
split the sea, and they went over on dry
ground. Now, in the future, let's read
about where it say staff here, and this
will be the last place. Zechariah 8.
Let's go in Zechariah the 8th chapter.
And when you get there, brother, pick it
up at that verse 3. But this is all
future here, and what a beautiful time
it's going to be. Zechariah 8 and 3 when
you get there, brother.
Thus saith the Lord, "I am returned unto
Zion, and will dwell in the midst of
Jerusalem. And Jerusalem shall be called
a city of truth, and the mountain of the
Lord of hosts, the holy mountain."
Thus saith the Lord of hosts, "There
shall yet old men and old women dwell
dwell in the streets of Jerusalem, and
every man with his staff in his hand for
very age." Oh, so here the Lord is
calling it a staff. Mhm. And this is all
future here.
And so, you can use the word rod and
staff interchangeably. It just depends
on the context of the story and how it's
being used.
Anybody else got something they'd like
to add?
All right. We'll leave it right there as
we move on to our next question with a
time check.
Yes, the time is 8:05. She also asks,
"Are
Levitical priests and the high priest
the same?"
Are Levitical priests and the high
priest, are they the same, brother
Julius?
No. They're from the same lineage, but
they're they're they're different
hierarchies of the priesthood.
You you had the high priest, you had the
priest, and then you had the Levites.
The high priest had what the highest
position. He had to wear the special
clothes. He had to go into the holy of
holies once a year.
He led the worships. He was the mediator
at that time.
Uh, so when Israel came out of Egypt,
you had
uh Aaron, the first high priest. After
him, Eleazar, and then Phinehas.
Then you had the priest who offered the
sacrifices. But then you had the Levites
who helped or assisted the priest. So,
they're not the same thing. They got
different jobs, but it's all a part of
the priesthood. That's all I got.
All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next.
Moving on. Adam asked for explanation of
144,000
and who are they. He says some believe
that it will only be the 144,000
that will make it into the kingdom.
Mhm. Boy, that really limits God there.
Guest caller.
Yeah, well,
uh who some believe is wrong.
That's right. This is when the Lord is
ready to pour his wrath out up on the
earth. Let's start this in in Revelation
the 6th chapter.
And just read
verse uh uh uh
6 uh 12 and 13, then we're going to
skip.
Okay.
Revelation 6 verses 12 and 13 say, "And
I beheld when he had opened the sixth
seal, and lo, there was a great
earthquake, and the sun became black as
sackcloth of hair, and the moon became
as blood. And the stars of heaven fell
unto the earth, even as a fig tree
casteth her untimely figs when she is
shaken of a mighty wind."
Now, when this happened, you got the
kings of the earth and the mighty men of
the earth, they started running and
running and hiding and asking and and
calling for the mountain and the rocks
to fall on them.
Why? Because the Lord is getting ready
to pour his wrath out on this earth.
Read that uh uh start at the
verse 16. See what these kings and all
of them
say. 16 and 17 when they saw heaven roll
back. Go ahead.
And said to the mountains and rocks,
"Fall on us, and hide us from the face
of him that sitteth on the throne, and
from the wrath of the Lamb.
For the great day of his wrath is come,
and who shall be able to stand?"
Uh-huh.
Now,
before that uh uh before he pour out his
wrath,
his servants will have gone through a
hard time, especially in this area,
because this area here is where the
beast and the false prophet ruled
directly. And that is just the full part
of the earth.
So, now, before he pour out his wrath,
he gave a commandment.
And let's look at this commandment.
Start at verse 7 and 1.
And after these things, I saw four
angels standing on the four corners of
the earth holding the four winds of the
earth, that the wind should not blow on
the earth, nor on the sea, nor on any
tree.
And I saw another angel ascending from
the east having the seal of the living
God. And he cried with a loud voice to
the four angels to whom it was given to
hurt the earth and the sea, saying,
"Hurt not the earth, neither the sea,
nor the trees till we have sealed the
servants of our God in their foreheads."
And I heard
All this is when Jesus is getting ready
to pour his wrath out.
These guys will have gone through a
rough time, but they have survived it.
And so, now Jesus said, "I want you to
seal my servant." That's right here in
this area.
That's where the beast and false prophet
are, because they only had direct
control over full part of the earth. So,
I want I want you to seal my servant,
cuz I don't want them to have to survive
the false prophets and the beast's
wrath. And now,
uh uh I'm going to pour my wrath out on
them? No, no. I want you to seal them.
And these and people only talks about
the 144,000,
but there was more than the 144,000 that
were sealed. Read verse 9.
After this, I beheld, and lo, a great
multitude, which no man could number, of
all nations, and kindreds, and people,
and tongues stood before the throne, and
before the Lamb, clothed with white
robes and palms in their hands.
Now, these was people These people only
talks about the 144,000,
but
you got other people out of every
kindred, tongue, and nation that was
also under the control of this beast and
false prophet directly. And they did not
receive a mark uh uh
uh
uh uh uh worship the beast and the false
prophet. So, now, question was asked,
who are these people?
So, we're going to start reading this at
verse 13.
And one of the
And one of the elders answered saying
unto me, "What are these which are
arrayed in white robes, and whence came
they?"
And I said unto him, "Sir, thou
knowest." And he said to me, "These are
they which came out of great
tribulation, and have washed their
robes, and made them white in the blood
of the lamb."
So, now these are the people really that
didn't get converted until it was under
the great tribulation.
And that's what it said it washed in
the blood of the lamb that mean that's
when they got converted during the great
tribulation.
So, keep reading.
Therefore, are they before the throne of
God, and serve him day and night in his
temple. And he that sitteth on the
throne shall dwell among them.
They shall hunger
Listen.
Listen. The Lord will be back on the
earth. Everybody on the planet will be
before the Lord then.
But these people was not in the first
resurrection. These are the flesh and
blood people.
And they was not changed when the Lord
came. And keep reading and it'll tell
you why. Keep reading.
They shall hunger no more, neither
thirst anymore. Neither shall the sun
light on them, nor any heat.
For the lamb which is in the midst of
the throne shall feed them, and shall
lead them unto living fountains of
waters, and God shall wipe away all
tears from their eyes. Yes. Now,
if if they was immortals,
then the Lord wouldn't have to
feed them.
And lead them to living waters. If you
have to lead them to living waters, that
mean that they going to have to be
taught
how to get salvation.
So, these was not immortals. These was
people that was converted during the
great tribulation, and the Lord
put his mark on them, so he would not
pour his wrath out on them when he was
doing the rest of the people that was
against them.
And once he get through and come to his
age, then he is going to lead them to
living waters. That mean they going to
have to be taught like everybody else.
But they are the people that survived
the great tribulation. They was not in
the first resurrection. They're still
flesh and blood. That's all I have to
say.
All right.
Thank you for that. We hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next.
Next one. They Adore Allie asks, "Are
the kidneys of animals supposed to be
eaten at all?"
And we'll open this up to the panel. If
it's a if it's comes from a clean
animal, as long as you don't eat the fat
or the blood, that's what the book say.
Anybody else?
There ain't nothing else to say.
Well, cuz the scripture don't say
nothing in Leviticus the 11th chapter or
Deuteronomy the 14th about what part of
the animal you can or cannot eat.
It just told you what animal you can or
cannot eat.
And like the brother said,
it only forbid you to drink the blood
and eat the fat.
All right.
So, we hope that that answered your
question as we move on.
Move on. The Boar Walder says, "When
reading Judges 11:31,
34,
and 39, it mentioned burnt offerings.
His daughter was the burnt offering,
right? So, what was the custom in
Israel?"
All right.
Go to Judges 11
and read and read the
places
so you can so
you will see what we're talking about
here.
Okay.
Judges 11 11 Mhm. Judge Judges 11 and
verse 31 says,
"Then it shall be that whatsoever cometh
forth of the doors of my house to meet
me when I return in peace from the
children of Ammon, shall surely be the
Lord's, and I will offer it up for burnt
offering."
Mhm. Verse 34 says, "And Jephthah came
to to Mizpah unto his house, and behold,
his daughter came out to meet him with
timbrels and with dances. And she was
his only child, because beside her, he
had neither son nor daughter."
"Verse 39 says, and it came to pass at
the end of two months that she returned
unto her father, who did with her
according to his vow which he had vowed,
and she knew no man, and it was a custom
in Israel."
Now, it was it was the custom in Israel.
We read We we missed it. Let's back up
and read from 34 to 39.
Okay.
It says,
"Verse 34, and Jephthah came to Mizpah
unto his house, and behold, his daughter
came out to meet him with timbrels and
and with dances. And she was his only
child, beside her, he had neither son
nor daughter.
And it came to pass when he saw her, he
rent his clothes, and said, 'Alas, my
daughter, thou has brought me very low,
and thou art one of them that trouble
me. For I have opened my mouth unto the
Lord, and I cannot go back.'"
"And she said unto him, 'My father, if
thou has opened thy mouth unto the Lord,
do to me according to that which
proceeded out of thy mouth. For as much
as the Lord has taken vengeance for thee
of thine enemies, even of the children
of Ammon.'"
"And she And she said unto her father,
'Let this thing be done for me. Let me
alone two months that I may go up and
down upon the mountain, and bewail my
virginity, I and my fellows.'" "And he
said, 'Go.' And he sent her away for two
months, and she went with her
companions, and bewailed her virginity
upon the mountains." "And it came to
pass at the end of the two months that
she returned unto her father, who did
with her according to his vow which he
had vowed, and she knew no man, and it
was a custom in Israel."
Now, the custom was, since that
happened,
all the young women,
every year for two months, would go and
bewail their virginity.
That was the custom.
Mhm. You know, it
Because uh
uh
there is no custom in Israel and and God
for
a people a a man to be sacrificed no
kind of way.
So, the only thing that you really
should have gotten out of here out of
this is that you should never vow a vow.
Because if you do,
let me show you what the Bible say about
it. Let's go into Ecclesiastes the fifth
chapter.
Read verses 4 through 6.
The Ecclesiastes 5:4-6
says,
"When thou vows a vow unto God, defer
not to pay it. For he hath no pleasure
in fools. Pay that which thou has vowed.
Better is it that thou shouldest not
vow, than that thou shouldest vow and
not pay.
Suffer not thy mouth to cause thy flesh
to sin. Neither say thou before the
angel that it was an error. Wherefore
should God be angry at thy voice, and
destroy the work of thine hands?"
So,
the the the lesson here is never vow a
vow to God for whatever the reason is.
Because if you fail to pay it, then the
Bible will call you a fool.
And the angel
that's that's that's standing before
you,
he ain't going to
give you a pass. He ain't going to
And you can't tell him, "Well, you know,
I made an error."
When you vow a vow, keep it. This man
vowed a vow, he had to keep it, but the
custom was
the request that his daughter made, "Let
me go up for two months and and bewail
my virginity." Her and her friends did
it. So, every year,
Israel used to do that.
The young women would go and and bewail
their uh virginities for two months in
the in the mountains and the hills. That
was the custom. That's all I have to
say. Mhm.
All right, that was a tough one there.
All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next.
Uh yes.
Um
going back to the 144,000,
someone says, "What are or who are the
144,000?"
Uh you gave who the other ones were, but
who are the 144,000?"
And they gave Revelation 14:1
and 3.
Are you talking about the new city
of a 144,000?
This is a different set.
Those were redeemed from the earth. Go
read it.
Okay.
Revelation
uh it has 14:1
and verses 4 and 5.
Revelation 14:1
says
Read all of
Read all the way through?
Mhm.
Okay.
Verse 1. And I looked, and lo, a Lamb
stood on the mount on the Mount Zion,
and with him 144,000,
having his Father's name written in
their foreheads.
And I heard a voice from heaven as the
voice of many waters, and as the voice
of a great thunder. And I heard the
voice of harpers harping with their
harps. And they sung as it were a new
song before the throne and before the
four beasts and the elders. And no man
could learn that song but the 144,000
which were redeemed from the earth.
These are they
Mhm.
This makes a difference right now. Now,
he said, "These was redeemed from the
earth."
The one in the seventh chapter,
the Lord said, "You got to lead and
guide them to living waters
Right.
along with a number that couldn't nobody
could number, but these was redeemed
from the earth. That mean that they was
in the first resurrection. Go ahead.
Yep.
These are they which were not defiled
with women, for they are virgins.
And here, that let you know that they
was all males then.
Mhm. They was not
That mean they was virgins. They ain't
never slept with a woman.
Go ahead.
These are they which follow the Lamb
whithersoever he goeth. These were
redeemed from among men, being the
firstfruits unto God and to the Lamb.
And in their mouth Mhm. They was they
was among the firstfruits.
Because
when the Lord came in the 20th chapter
of Revelation, he said, "The people that
been beheaded
and didn't receive them all," he said,
"they ruled they they reigned with
Christ 1,000 years. This is the first
resurrection."
Mhm. But these
was males
and they hadn't slept with women. But go
ahead and read.
Being the firstfruits unto God and to
the Lamb.
And in their mouth was found no guile,
for they are without fault before the
throne of God.
Now,
this is the question of part. They was
out guile. That mean they never told a
lie. They ain't never did nothing wrong.
I cannot even imagine a person that's
got grown
with no guile in their mouth. Because
Jesus is called the holy one of Israel.
Right.
And then once uh
when the young man asked Jesus in the
19th chapter of Matthew,
"What should I do do to get salvation?"
He said, "Good master, what should I do
to get salvation, to get eternal life?"
And Jesus told him, "Why callest thou me
good? There ain't none good but God."
That mean that as long as he would even
in the flesh, Jesus wouldn't even carry
the title of good. But here's people
that never told a lie, they had never
slept with women,
and they was in the first resurrection
because they redeemed from the earth.
I don't know. There's no scripture to
tell you who these were,
but uh
my opinion, and my opinion only, no
scripture,
is that these had to be the male babies
that died with Moses
when they when they tried to kill them,
and also the male babies that died with
Jesus.
That's the only time when male babies
was killed.
And a baby's about the only thing
And a baby's about the only thing that's
died that they ever had the opportunity
to to tell a lie.
But as far as they being these young
men,
I want you to understand, everybody
that's listening, that is my opinion. I
have no scripture for that.
But I come to that conclusion because
they was male, they never lied,
they ain't never touched a woman,
and they was redeemed from the earth.
Mhm. That means
immortal. They was in the first
resurrection. That's the best I can do
with that.
Yep. All right.
Hope that shed some light shed some
light on your question as we
move on to our next one.
Yes, we are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, June the 25th, 2025.
Mark says, "I thought apostles were
defined as witnesses of Jesus'
resurrection.
How can we have apostles today in modern
day times?"
All right. How can we have apostles
today in these modern times, guest
caller?
Well, the thing is,
you know,
he thought I'd like to know where uh uh
uh
where you get your source of information
from.
So, there ain't nothing written in the
understanding that you can only have
apostles in Jesus' day.
But I'll do this, we'll read a few
things and see what we get. Let's go
into Luke the 11th chapter and read
verse 49.
Okay.
Luke 11 and verse 49 says, "Therefore
also said the wisdom of God, I will send
them prophets and apostles, and some of
them they shall slay and persecute."
Now,
this mean that he going to send them.
You think it's the only generation that
he sent apostles was
in in in Jesus' day?
No.
That's the one that was taken up. Go to
Ephesians 4
and read from 7 to 12.
Okay. Ephesians 4:7-12
says, "But unto every one of us is given
grace according to the measure of the
gift of Christ. Wherefore he saith, When
he ascended up on high, he led captivity
captive and gave gifts unto men.
Now that he ascended, what is it but
that he also descended first into the
lower parts of the earth?
He that descended is the same also that
ascended up far above all heavens, that
he might
fulfill all fulfilled all things.
And he gave some apostles and some
prophets and some evangelists and some
pastors and teachers for the perfecting
of the saints, for the work of the
ministry, for the edifying of the body
of Christ." Yep. If
you got no apostles uh uh
nowadays, then you ain't got no
teachers, you don't have no ministers,
you don't have any of these people.
This is talking about in every
generation.
It's all
And
uh uh as far as uh look at first 2
Timothy
verses 1 and skip down and read verse
11.
2 Timothy
What chapter again?
First chapter.
First chapter. First chapter and
verse
Verse 1
and and 11. Okay. Verse 1 says, "Paul,
an apostle of Jesus Christ by the will
of God, according to the promise of life
which is in Christ Jesus.
Verse 11 says, "Whereunto I am appointed
a preacher and an apostle and a teacher
of the Gentiles."
It says that Paul was a was a preacher
and a teacher and an apostle to the
Gentiles. He wasn't a part of Israel.
He came later. He did not witness Jesus'
resurrection. He came way after the
resurrection of Jesus. And the church
was so big until Paul became a part of
them that persecuted the church.
Yep.
But let's look and see uh uh another one
other place. Let's go into Revelation
18th chapter. This is talking about this
fall taking down of Babylon the Great,
which is the European Union.
We're going to read verse 1 and 2 and
skip down and read verse 20.
Okay.
Uh Revelation 18:1 and 2 says, "And
after these things, I saw another angel
come down from heaven, having great
power, and the earth was lightened with
his glory. And he cried mightily with a
strong voice, saying, 'Babylon the Great
is fallen, is fallen, and is become the
habitation of devils and the hold of
every foul spirit, and a cage of every
unclean and hateful bird.'"
Now, Babylon the Great is the European
Union. That even happened That haven't
happened yet. That's beyond us, isn't
it?
Yep. Let's skip down to verse 20 and
read it.
Rejoice over her, thou heaven, and ye
holy apostles and prophets, for God hath
avenged you on her.
So, the whole thing is
that they they can't rejoice
until the woman have been Babylon have
been taken down because God have avenged
you on her. That mean that Jesus here.
European Union is taken down.
Babylon agreement is taking place.
And then he said for the apostles to
rejoice. Read that 20th verse again.
Rejoice over her, thou heaven, and ye
holy apostles and prophets, for God hath
avenged you on her.
Okay?
So, that mean that we got some we going
to even now we got some we have apostles
because uh that's speaking to the people
in the future.
But it's for us
uh uh apostles being a witness
to Jesus.
Israel is a witness to Jesus when he was
Jehovah or Yahweh and he's still a
witness right now.
Isaiah 43
10 12
20 and 21.
Isaiah 43 verses 10 through 12 says
Ye are my witnesses, saith the Lord, and
my servant who I have chosen. That ye
may know and believe me, and understand
that I am he. Before me there was no God
formed, neither shall there be after me.
I, even I am the Lord, and beside me
there is no savior. I have declared and
have saved. I have showed when there was
no strange god among you. Therefore, ye
are my witnesses, saith the Lord, that I
am God.
Now, he's talking about Israel is the
witness that he is God. Skip down to
verse 20 and 21.
The beast of the field shall honor me.
The dragons and the owls, because I gave
waters in the wilderness and rivers in
the desert to give drink to my people,
my chosen.
This people have I formed for myself.
They shall show forth my praise.
Now,
that's in before and after Jesus.
And you can tell who the apostles are of
Jesus. They're the ones that teaching
that the kingdom is going to be on the
earth. They're the ones that teach that
Jesus is going to sit on David's throne.
They're the ones that uh speaks
that the seventh day, which is called
Saturday, is the Lord's Sabbath day.
I am an apostle and everybody that's
teaching his word,
especially Israelites, we are
the Lord's witnesses before and after.
That makes us apostles. That's all I
have to say.
Amen. Indeed. All right. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one with the time check. Yes,
moving on. The time is 8:34.
This cutie asked, "If someone can't
afford circumcision,
does that mean they can't get saved?
Excuse me, does that mean they can't get
salvation?"
No.
But in order to
be in the kingdom of God, you have to be
guest called.
Right. Let's read some scripture on
that.
Let's go with that Exodus to the 17th
chapter.
Are you in 17?
I think it's uh 17.
Uh 14, maybe.
Genesis 17, you want?
Exodus
this first.
Was it Genesis?
Read it. Somebody. Okay. 17.
Yeah, you want to start off with Abram?
Abraham?
Right.
Go ahead. Start it there.
So,
Genesis 17.
Okay.
All right.
Uh verse to start at chapter 1, meaning
at verse 1?
Yeah, that's a good place. Okay. And
when Abram was 90 years old and nine,
the Lord appeared to Abram and said unto
him, "I am the almighty God. Walk before
me and be thou perfect.
And I will make my covenant between me
and thee and will multiply thee
exceedingly.
And Abram fell on his face
Now, skip down to verse 9. We going to
get directly to the to the covenant.
Skip down to verse 9 and go to
verse 10, rather. Okay.
This is my covenant, which ye shall
keep.
Okay.
Pick it verse 9.
Okay. Verse 9. And God said unto
Abraham, "Thou shalt keep my covenant.
Therefore, thou and thy seed after thee
in their generations.
This is my covenant, which ye shall keep
between me and you and thy seed after
thee. Every man child among you shall be
circumcised.
Ye Ye shall Ye shall circumcise the
flesh of your foreskin, and it shall be
a token of the covenant betwixt me and
you.
And he that is eight days eight days old
shall be circumcised among you. Every
man child in
Uh-huh. Now, this is God
This is not This is not Moses. This is
God talking now. And he is talking to
Abraham. Keep reading.
Every man in your generations, he that
is born in the house or bought with
money of any stranger, which is not of
thy seed.
He that is born in thy house and he that
is brought with thy money must needs be
circumcised. And my covenant shall be
The two strong words, isn't it? Very
strong.
Both of them are absolutes. Isn't that
Isn't that correct? That's correct.
Ain't no maybe they should be maybe they
don't have to must
needs be circumcised. You keep going.
And my covenant shall be in your flesh
for an everlasting covenant. And the
uncircumcised man child, whose flesh of
his foreskin is not circumcised, that
soul shall be cut off from his people.
He hath broken my covenant.
Wait a minute now. Who said that?
God did.
the Lord.
Now,
so uh uh
what can we do with that when you look
at that? He going to break from my
covenant. What verse was that? That was
14.
Okay. Now,
he said he shall be cut off from among
his brethren. Ain't that right? Yes.
Mhm.
Did you finish that? Yes, I did.
Now, let's go into Exodus the 12th
chapter.
And we going to start with the with the
uh uh
with the
orders of the Passover.
43.
Okay.
Reverend 23.
43. Exodus 12 and 43.
Okay. Read it.
And the Lord said unto Moses and Aaron,
"This is the ordinance of the Passover.
There shall no stranger
Now, everybody know what the Passover
is. The Lord killed the lamb.
He told them to put the blood over the
doorpost. In fact, let's read that. Let
Let we going to read it because when he
come through to kill everybody, he is
going to when he see the blood, he going
to pass over you. So, why don't we back
up Why don't we read that first before
we get to the orders of the Passover?
Because uh
we need to know
that this question is going to be is
answered by God.
Okay?
Let's back up to 12
and uh
it tell you to keep going and you going
to
the 14th day. Put it up until the 14th
day.
Go ahead. That's represent Jesus.
Okay.
And we are we're starting at
uh
Let's see here. We You said start at
verse 1?
Well, we can start at verse 1 and we
going
Okay.
And the Lord spake unto Moses and Aaron
in the land of Egypt saying, "This month
shall be unto you the beginning of
months. It shall be the first month of
the year to you.
Speak ye unto all the congregation of
Israel saying, 'In the 10th day of this
month, they shall take to them every man
a lamb according to the house of their
fathers, a lamb for a house.
Uh-huh. And it
You can skip to five. Okay.
Your lamb shall be without blemish, a
male of the first year. You shall take
it out from the sheep or from the goats.
And you shall keep it up until the 14th
day of the same month. And the whole
assembly of the congregation of Israel
shall kill it in the evening.
And they shall take of the blood and
strike it on the two side posts and on
the upper door posts of the houses
wherein they shall eat it.
And they shall eat
Mhm.
Verse 12.
Okay.
For I will pass through the land of
Egypt this night and will smite all the
firstborn in the land of Egypt, both man
and beast. And against all the gods of
Egypt, I will execute judgment. I am the
Lord.
And the blood shall be to you for a
token upon the houses where you are. And
when I see the blood, I will pass over
you and the plague shall not be upon you
to destroy you when I smite the land of
Egypt.
Now, that's the blood of that lamb. When
he see the blood, he going to pass over
you.
And he won't kill the firstborn in your
household. He didn't say it because I'm
going to pass over you because you're
Israelite. I'm going to pass over you
because you good or bad. He said, "When
I see the blood." Because this is going
to be a token to you. That means that's
the token of your faith.
You heard what the Lord told you to do
and you did it. And you did the works
because uh uh faith is is is is is uh uh
defined by your works. Okay? So, now.
Now, let's go down to verse 40. Let's
skip to verse 40 42.
Okay.
Verse 42
43.
Okay. Verse 43
Huh?
Okay. It says, "And the Lord said unto
Moses and Aaron, this is the ordinance
of the Passover. There shall no stranger
eat thereof.
But every man servant that is bought for
money, when thou has circumcised him,
then shall he eat thereof."
A foreigner
Mhm. No stranger.
You got to be circumcised, didn't it?
Skip down to 47 and go here.
And uh I'm sorry, not and, but 47 says,
"All the congregation of Israel shall
keep it.
And when a stranger shall sojourn with
thee and will keep the Passover to the
Lord, let all his males be circumcised.
And then let him come near and keep it.
And he shall be as one that is born in
the land. For no uncircumcised person
shall eat thereof."
"One law shall be to him that is
homeborn and unto the stranger that
sojourneth among you."
Thus did all
Mhm.
So, that means can't nobody
uncircumcised
take part of the Passover. Isn't that
what they're saying here? Correct.
Let's go and find out who the who this
Passover represent and who is the real
Passover.
Let's go into 1 Corinthians 5 and 7.
Mhm.
1 Corinthians 5 and 7 says,
"Purge out therefore the old leaven that
he may be a new lump as you are
unleavened. For even Christ our Passover
is sacrificed for us."
Now, according to what we just read in
the second 12th chapter of Exodus,
can you take part of Christ being that
he's the Passover?
No.
No. Okay, then. So, then he told And so,
how is it then that you will become a uh
Abraham's seed then? Cuz he's the only
one that God made a promise to.
So, let's go into Galatians the third
chapter.
"For Christ our Passover is sacrificed
for us." That means that he is the
sacrifice.
And the Lord said, "No uncircumcised
person
shall take part, you know, uh uh of the
Passover." Now, let's go into Galatians
the third chapter.
And we're going to start reading at
verse 26. Because uh uh
because it said that uh that uh Christ
is our Passover.
So, we going to see how we become the
children of God. Verse 26.
Okay.
Galatians 3 verse 26 says, "For you are
all the children of God by faith in
Christ Jesus. For as many of you as have
been baptized into Christ have put on
Christ.
There is neither There is neither Jew
nor Greek. There is neither bond nor
free. There is neither male nor female.
For you are all one in Christ Jesus. And
if you be Christ,
Cuz he is the Passover.
I keep reading.
"And if you be Christ, then are you
Abraham's seed and heirs according to
the promise."
Now, we have a a double uh uh
uh uh
answer here.
If you going to take part
of the Passover,
you got to be circumcised and Christ is
the Passover. In order for you to become
also Abraham's seed, you also got to got
to be baptized in Christ. That's right.
Then you are heirs according then are
you Abraham's seed
and are heirs according to the promise.
So, what did the Lord tell Abraham
and what Abraham and his seed must do?
Get circumcised. Must be circumcised.
Must needs be circumcised.
So.
Uh-huh. And if they don't do it, what
what's going to happen to them?
They have broken his covenant and shall
be cut off from my name people.
Cut off from among his people. That
means they got to die. Now,
whoever asked this question, you decide.
That's all I have to say.
Mhm.
And if you can't afford the
circumcision, you keep praying. God will
make a way.
Of course, he will.
Yes.
All right. Hope that answered your
question and we're going to move on to
our next one. As time is ticking.
Yes. Let's move on. Um Kim Noel asks,
"Do the men
that are called the elders of the church
supposed to be a certain age or does it
depend
on how long they have been in the
church?"
Yes, caller.
The Bible don't give no
restrictions one way or the other. The
only thing that the Bible give a
restriction is
is when men wanted to be teachers and
ministers.
Let's go into Numbers the fourth
chapter.
And we're going to read
one, two,
and skip down and read 4 to 6 and 4 to
7.
Okay.
Numbers the fourth chapter verse one and
two says,
"And the Lord spake unto Moses and unto
Aaron saying, take the sum of the sons
of Kohath from among the sons of Levi
and after their families by the house of
their fathers
from 30 years old and upward even unto
50 years old, all that enter into the
host to do the work in the tabernacle of
the congregation."
Uh-huh.
And then
Okay.
What's the next verse?
46 and 47.
46 and 47 says, "From
I mean, I'm sorry. 46 says, "All those
that were numbered of the Levites whom
Moses and Aaron and the chief of Israel
numbered after their families and after
the house of their fathers from 30 years
old and upward even unto 50 years old,
everyone that came to do the service of
the ministry and the service of the
burden in the tabernacle of the
congregation."
So, that is the only age restriction
that the uh that's given.
As for the elders in the church,
whether they've been old or appointed or
either somebody appointed by the church,
I suppose that's that's left to
discretion of whatever the congregation
they in.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
We're going to leave it right there as
we move on to our next question.
Yes. She also asks,
"Is Israel in northern Africa because it
was the land of Canaan and he is the son
of Ham," she says.
"The land of Africa was called the land
of Ham.
Can you explain we came through Africa,
not from Africa?"
All right. Yes, caller. What you say?
Well, no When you say northern Africa,
that is Egypt.
That's northern Africa.
But as far as God did give the land of
Israel give the land of Canaan, which is
Ham's first son, to Israel. At time it
was called the land of Ham.
And the word Africa wasn't even in
existence.
So when the word Africa came into
existence,
the Lord had already changed the land of
Canaan to the land of Israel.
So now, and that is
east
of the African continent.
So we come from Israel. We did not come
off of the continent of Africa.
Because
where we came from is called the Middle
East now, which it still is Israel.
That's why
it is said
that we came through Africa, not out of
Africa, because 70 AD, when Titus
uh uh uh 700 AD, 700 BC rather,
when the Assyrians took Israel,
they scattered uh uh uh
Israel
into
a lot of the African countries, and
sometime in the uh uh uh even uh uh uh
East Eu- Europe.
And then in 70 AD,
Titus scattered Judah
to
all over the Mediterraneans, which is
Europe, a part of them is north of the
Mediterranean, which is Europe, and
south of the Mediterranean is the
continent of Africa. And that's where
and uh put together a whole lot of
history that go there.
But that's where they took
the slave of trans- transatlantic trade
uh uh
trade
slave trade. So yeah.
That was off of Africa.
So we had taken out of Israel,
taken to Europe and to Africa, and then
a lot of the Europeans took the babies
and they created a
place on in on the African continent,
and they called it
uh uh the nation of Judah.
But Israel did not originate there.
Israel originated
in the land of Canaan, which was
west of the African continent. And it
was called Israel before the name Africa
came into existence.
Yeah. Therefore, when the Lord took us
out of our land,
on our way to America, we came through
Africa.
In the transatlantic
trade
slave trade.
So that's the that's all I have to say.
All right.
That's some good history right there. As
we move on, Sister Deborah, time is a
ticking.
Yes, Deborah Pasha asks, "Those who
missed the first resurrection,
are they not also going to be tormented
by Satan and his angels during this
time?"
Uh Rev- uh uh Revelation 20:7-9
is given.
Brother Jerome, shed some light on this
resurrection, brother.
Let's go read it. Revelation 20
7-9.
Okay.
And when the thousand years are expired,
Satan shall be loosed out of his prison,
and shall go out to deceive the nations
which are in the four quarters of the
earth, Gog and Magog, to gather them
together to battle. The number of whom
is as the sand of the sea.
And they went up on the breadth of the
earth, and compassed the camp of the
saints about, and the beloved city. And
fire came down from God out of heaven,
and devoured them.
Okay.
I think we're trying to put this in
chronological order.
Uh
you know, soon after the first
resurrection,
uh Satan going to be chained.
And he going to be put in a bottomless
pit.
Okay?
And so Satan won't be tormenting anybody
while he's in a bottomless pit
for a thousand years.
Okay?
So those verses that you gave, these are
events that's going to happen when he is
loosed
from his thousand years in the pit. All
right? So now let's go to the
Revelation. Let's stay in that
Revelation 20 and pick it up at verse
one, read it to the three. Okay.
And I saw an angel come down from
heaven, having the key of the bottomless
pit and a great chain in his hand.
And he laid hold on the dragon, that old
serpent, which is the devil and Satan,
and bound him a thousand years. All
right. So now he going to be bound and
put in this pit bottomless pit, he not
going to be tormenting nobody. He
chained up
for a whole thousand years.
Okay, go ahead.
And cast him into the bottomless pit,
and shut him up, and set a seal upon
him, that he should deceive the nations
no more, till the thousand years should
be fulfilled. And after that, he must be
loosed a little season.
All right. So now when Satan is loose
for a little season, right? He going to
be loosed in the latter part
of the thousand year reign of Christ.
All right?
He going to That's that little season.
He going to be loose a little season
within the thousand year reign of
Christ.
After his thousand years, Satan's
thousand years is expired.
He going to be loosed a little season.
Now look, these are the verses that you
uh had uh put in your question. So pick
it up back up at the verse seven. Okay.
Go ahead.
And when the thousand years are expired,
Satan shall be loosed out of his prison,
and shall go out to deceive the nations
which are in the four quarters of the
earth, Gog and Magog, to gather them
together to battle. The number of whom
is as the sand of the sea.
And they went up on the breadth of the
earth, and compassed the camp of the
saints about, and the beloved city. And
fire came down from God out of heaven,
and devoured them.
Okay. So when he got loose, he still
wasn't tormenting
nobody. He was deceiving them, though,
cuz that's what the verse said. He
deceiving these nations, and he
deceiving them to uh encamp around the
camp of the the uh surround the camp of
the saints. Now these saints and and and
and and and these people are flesh and
blood.
Okay?
That's who he's surrounding.
All right? That's in the holy city,
which we know is Jerusalem.
All right? And when he deceive them,
then fire going to come down from heaven
and devour these people who he deceived
to gather around the camp of the saints.
And he going to kill everyone and then
that fire going to kill every last one
of them
that tried to destroy the camp of the
saints that's in the holy city.
All right? Then Satan going to get cast
in the lake of fire, because the lake of
fire ain't the pit.
All right? He going to be in that lake
of fire. As a matter of fact, the two
witnesses
I'm sorry. Whoo.
The beast and the false prophet already
in that lake of fire
by the time Satan get cast in that fire
after he deceived the nations to gather
uh uh around the camp of the saints.
Okay? So
um what what verse you at?
That That was verse nine. Go ahead and
read.
And the devil that deceived them was
cast into the lake of fire and
brimstone, where the beast and the false
prophet are. They already was there.
By the time he got there, they was
already there. Go ahead. And shall be
tormented day and night forever and
ever. Yeah. So that that's all I got on
it. Anybody want to add something. All
right.
Thank you for that, brother. Sister
Deborah, let's try and squeeze these two
more questions in there before we leave.
Go right ahead. Yes, or at least one
more after that for the live. But Cassia
Lee asks, "Are groups such as Eastern
Stars and the Masons demonic?
Are there any scriptures denouncing
these groups?"
Brother Julius.
Eastern Stars and Masons are
fraternities
with secrets.
Uh they have uh rights. They have
different levels, different
organizations.
And uh in my study of them, cuz my
father was one,
uh they have a title called Worshipful
Master.
You know,
let's go to Let's look what Jesus said
about it. Let's go to Matthew the 23rd
chapter.
Matthew 23,
we're going to read verses 9 and 10.
Okay. Matthew 23:9-10
says, "And call no man your father upon
the earth, for one is your father which
is in heaven. Uh-huh. Neither be ye
called masters, for one is your master,
even Christ. So, therefore, if it's if
it's contrary to scripture,
you make that determination.
We have to go by what the book say.
That's all I got on that.
All right.
Thank you for that, brother. Next
question.
Sean Leah says, in Luke 6:35
and Psalms 37:21,
"If I shouldn't expect my brother to pay
me back after I lend him money, then how
come an evil man borrows without
repaying? I don't get it."
Brother Dre, help them to get it.
Yeah, let's go to that Psalm 37 first.
Psalm 37 and we go
verse 21.
All right. It says,
"The wicked borroweth and pray and
payeth not again, but the righteous
showeth mercy and giveth."
And that that is two separate things
right there. We talking about the wicked
borrowing.
They're borrowing.
So, they're not asking for something
and they borrow and pay not again.
But, the righteous showeth mercy and
giveth. So, the righteous may give the
money to the person that needed.
He's showing mercy to them.
That's all that's saying. What is there
not to get about it? Let's go to Luke 6
now. Luke 6 and 35. Read that.
It says,
"But, love ye your enemies and do good
and lend, hoping for nothing again. And
your reward shall be great and you shall
be the children of the highest, for he
is kind unto the unthankful and to the
evil."
So, if you are in a position of giving,
you are in a better position of them
that have to receive.
And it says here, "Do good and lend,
hoping for nothing again.
And your reward will be great."
So, what's wrong with that?
We should get that.
If we in the position to give and you
can give, give.
That's all I got.
Ready to give than to receive, right,
brother? Yes, sir.
All right. Final question of the
evening. Quickly, Deborah, we'll go open
it up to the panel.
Yes, Hinga Israel says, "I need some
understanding on this law. Deuteronomy
23:3
and Nehemiah 13:1.
If so, how was Ruth able to be married
to Boaz?
Also, how does this law relate in
today's time?"
Deuteronomy 23 and 3.
Go ahead, brother, when you get there.
Deuteronomy 23 and 3 says,
"An Ammonite or Moabite shall not enter
into the congregation of the Lord, even
to their 10th generation shall they not
enter into the congregation of the Lord
forever."
And the other one is Nehemiah 13:1.
Nehemiah 13
Second Chronicles, Ezra, Nehemiah.
Nehemiah 13 and verse 1 says, "On that
day they read in the book of Moses in
the audience of the people and therein
was found written that the Ammonite and
the Moabite should not come into the
congregation of God forever."
Question, Deborah, and then the panel.
Yes, so the question
Hinga gives is, "So, how was Ruth able
to marry
uh to Boaz? And how does this law relate
in today's time?"
Yes, Carlin, you got some light for that
question?
All right.
It looks like we'll have to do some
further research on that one.
So, uh time check, Deborah.
This is talking about the time to do it.
The time is what?
The time is 9:05.
Brother Julius, what you say? Said this
is talking about the priesthood. This
has nothing to do with Ruth.
Oh, okay.
With that being the being the case, then
we would need a
a resubmit. But, we're going to Deal
with it next week.
Yeah, we're going to um
thank everybody for tuning in with us
this evening.
We had a good time answering your
questions. So, we like to say
that if you submitted a question and we
didn't get to it, don't resubmit it.
Sister Deborah take it, put it in a
rotation. And like brother Julius say,
next week we can give that question some
attention. So, until we all come
together again, thank you all for
viewing. Be blessed, be safe, stay
prayed up and may the Lord have mercy on
us all as our brother closes us which
art in heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy
kingdom come, thy will be done in earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread and
forgive us our debts as we forgive our
debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil,
for thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever. In Jesus' name.